准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
章爸的
恶作剧商店
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
悲惨的新一天又悲惨地开始了
Another miserable start to another miserable day
你好
Greetings
你一看就身心健康  胸怀幽默
You strike me as a man with a healthy sense of humor
小子  我有优惠要给你
Well, boy, do I have just the offer for you
保证实惠到可以让你
It's a deal you can really sink
咬牙切齿狠狠投入
your chattering teeth into
还不止呢
But that's not all
喜不喜欢咬口香糖啊
Do you like to snap your gum?
这个口香糖呢
Well this gum
可以咬你
snaps you
想把无价小道具带回家
These priceless gags can be yours
只要二十四块九毛九的低价
for the low, low price of 24.99
不过现在购买
But if you act now
还能额外赠送一套牛排刀
I'll throw in a free set of steak knives
你闹够了没  爸
Are you finished now, Dad?
你怎么认出来是我的
How did you know it was me?
带我进去坐坐吧  儿子
Bring it in, son
我新定了条推销路线  刚飞来这
I just flew into town on my new sales route
就想到顺路来看看你
and thought I would drop by
顺便考虑要在这暂留几天
And also thought I would stay for a few days
你
You--
什么
What?
真了不起  小章
Very impressive, Squiddy
你真这么觉得吗
You really think so?
当然了
Of course
我就爱看小丑画
I love clown paintings
开心点嘛  儿子
Cheer up, son
要不你给我吹首
Why don't you play me
你那特好听的竖笛曲吧
one of your famous clarinet tunes?
我最近确实在练新曲子
Well, I have been practicing a new song
这是经典款吹泡泡竖笛
It's the classic bubble-blowing clarinet
只要六块九毛九
It's only 6.99
这一定会是我这辈子最漫长的几天
This will be the longest few days of my life
爸
Dad
你喇叭就不能小点声吗
Can you keep your honking down?
不好了
Oh, no
要是你们喜欢尖叫鸡
If you like rubber chickens
就肯定会爱上这自行车喇叭
you'll love this bicycle horn
没错  小子们
That's right, boys
我这儿的喇叭多得是
I've got horns-a-plenty
雾号
Fog horns
法国圆号
French horns
大喇叭
Bull horns
牛
全都只要九块九毛九
Just 9.99 each
主流的信用卡我都收哦
I take all major credit cards
不过这卡我保证会还回去
But I promise, I give them all back
拜托  别给我烦人的邻居
Please, do not arm my annoying neighbors
配备更烦人的道具
with even more annoying props
我求你了  老爸
I'm begging you, Father
什么
What?
章鱼哥  他是你爸吗
Squidward, this is your dad?
我还以为蟹老板是你爸
I thought Mr. Krabs was your dad
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
你们别来烦我跟爸  我会不胜感激
And I would appreciate it
if you left my father and I alone
没事的
Come on
章鱼哥
Squidward
一起来嘛
Join in
玩一下又不会受伤
It's just harmless fun
对啊  无伤大雅又好玩
Yeah, harmless fun
握个手吧  派大星
Put her there, Patrick
好
Yeah
不要
No
来  我扶你们两个起来
Here, let me help you two up
今天算是一场空
Well, today was a wash
还是明天再来吧
Guess I'll try again tomorrow
我就只要睡上个
I just need to sleep for
二十三小时半就好了
Twenty-three and a half hours
有我这专利放屁床  保证你会是活宝
You'll be the life of the slumber party
with my patented whoopee bed
别来烦我
Leave me alone
有个橡皮梯子就是方便
Always handy to have a rubber ladder
好了
Here it is
哒哒
Ta-da
这样才叫快闪店
Now, that's what I call a pop-up store
弹
章爸的
恶作剧商店
快来参观
Step right up to
章爸的恶作剧商店
Jeffy T's Prankwell Emporium
我是恶作剧小贩
I'm a peddler of pranks
整活货郎  恶搞店主
a giver of gags, a trader of tricks
如有需要
You need it
新奇小道具我差不多都有卖
I sell a novelty approximation of it
你朋友会说
Your friends will be saying
好多恶作剧
"Prank's a lot"
我倒要说这恶作剧都是白费力气
Well, I'm saying pranks for nothing
谁能想得到章鱼哥的老爸
Who would have thought Squidward's dad
居然会这么有趣
would be such a lively guy?
对啊
Yeah
他让我好想笑
He makes me laugh
章  章鱼哥反倒让我很难过
S-Squidward just makes me sad
胡说八道
Nonsense
章鱼哥有自己的一套搞笑法
Squidward is hilarious in his own right
虽然他名叫章鱼哥
I mean, his name is Squidward
鱿 鱼
但他可是章鱼
but he's an octopus
简直就是我最棒的恶作剧之一
That was one of my best pranks
真好笑
That's a good one
能再看点你的新奇恶作剧吗  章先生
Can we see more of your novelty gags, Mr. Tentacles?
我儿子才那么叫
Please, Mr. Tentacles is my son
叫我章爸才对
Call me Jeffy
好东西还有不少呢
There's more where that came from
这是一点我的原型恶搞道具
Here are just a few of my prototype gags
斑点肥皂
Polka dot soap
有点棒
Dot's great
隐形鱿鱼墨水
Disappearing squid ink
裤子钱可以省下不少了
Think of all the money I'll save on pants
别忘了我的炸弹冰棍
And don't forget my bombsicles
酷
Cool
没错
That's right
我职业生涯里开发出了几千样恶作剧
I've developed thousands of gags
over the course of my career
最近我还在研发
I've even been working on
终极恶作剧
the ultimate gag
不过目前还没准备好
But it's just not ready yet
基本没什么头绪
I can't seem to figure it out
我们可以帮忙
We can help
对
Yeah
看看你的新恶作剧  章爸哥先生
Show us your new gags, Mr. Jeffyward
真是好主意  小子
Brilliant idea, boys
要不你们来我测试厨房里吧
Why don't you step into my test kitchen
这地方看着好像章鱼哥家的厨房
You know, this looks a lot like Squidward's kitchen
当作我的恶搞实验室就行
Think of it as my gag lab
我在里面安插了我最新的几个恶作剧
I've planted some of my newest pranks around
比如说
For instance
米虫
Rice lice
总有几个谁厨艺巨烂
Some people are so bad at cooking
连水都不会烧
they can't even boil water
家里有烧火壶就更不会烧水了
Especially not with a flammable pot
他得把烈火器给找来
He better grab that fire re-stinguisher
给  儿子
Here, son
用这朵喷射花
Use this squirting flower
这才是真正的灭火器
It's the real fire extinguisher
起码火确实灭了
Well, at least the fire's out
我动不了了
I'm stuck
那是因为
That's because
这也是方便面包
it's also instant bread
哒哒
Ta-da
趁热吃吧
Get it while it's hot
这可是超火清仓大甩卖
It's a fire sale
谁想来买点乐子啊
Now, who wants to buy some fun?
够了
That's it
我要到没有乐子的地方去
I'm going where there won't be any fun
上班
Work
什么
What?
等一下
Wait a minute
我的眼角膜
My cornea
这钱不对劲
Something's wrong with this money
最好跟蟹老板报告一下
I better go tell Mr. Krabs
什么
What?
我才不会去收拾那玩意
I'm not cleaning that up
怎么了  章鱼哥
What's wrong, Squidward?
你牙齿看着怎么比平常还诡异
Why do your teeth look weirder than usual?
橡皮牙齿
Rubber teeth
这个是橡皮落地食物
And this is a rubber spill
还有橡皮钱
And rubber money
我这些恶作剧道具都是找你爸买的
I bought all these pranks from your dad
是不是很搞笑啊
Aren't they hilarious?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝又在讨人厌了
SpongeBob is being obnoxious again
整到你了
Got ya
这是我举世闻名的橡皮老板
It's my famous rubber boss
只要九十九块九毛九
For only 99.99
我再也受不了了
I can't take it anymore
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
你爸卖我这个巨型水气球
Your dad sold me this giant water balloon
才四十九块九毛九
Only 49.99
接着
Catch
完了
Oh, no
里面全是水母
It's full of jellyfish
现在该做点我很早就该做的事情了
Now to do something I should've done a long time ago
漂亮的宝贝
Beautiful baby
那么  我挚爱的老爸
So, daddy dearest
你喜欢恶作剧是吧
You like pranks, do ya?
我倒要给你点让你永生难忘的恶作剧
I'll give this some pranks you'll never forget
早安  儿子
Morning, son
看着还是和平常一样活泼嘛
Looking chipper as always
我要送你一样礼物  老爸
I have a present for you, Father
送我吗
For me?
没那必要吧
You shouldn't have
可你真该收下
But you really deserve it
不知道会是什么呢
I wonder what it could be
惊喜拳击手套
A surprise boxing glove?
我太爱了
I love it
还有奶油派
And a cream pie?
这奶油还是痒痒膏
With itching cream
还有臭屁弹
And a stink bomb too
儿子
Son
就是这个了
This is it
终极恶作剧
The ultimate gag
别动我小指啊
Not my pinky
很好笑吧
Pretty funny, right?
来玩到昏头昏脑吧
Here, knock yourselves out
好耶
Yeah
你的的确确很像你老爸了
You certainly take after your old man
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you
你帮我做出了终极恶作剧
for figuring out my ultimate gag
现在我能跟全世界共享了
Now I can share it with the world
我这就去打包行李  马上出发
I'll just go pack up my things and head out
真的吗
Really?
我就想听你这么说
That's all I ever wanted to hear you say
整到你了
Got ya
舌尖上的
痞老板
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
现在回到  海洋恶心生物世界
And now back to The World of Gross Sea Life
海洋恶心生物
世界
看这机敏的等足类寄生虫
Observe how this ingenious parasitic isopod
附在鱼嘴里化为舌头  找到了新家
finds a new home by attaching itself
inside a fish's mouth, becoming its new tongue
那是我见过最恶心的东西了
That's the most disgusting thing I've ever seen
既恶心又天才
Disgustingly genius
让我想到了个绝佳好办法
It's giving me a wonderful idea
我要把自己粘到海绵宝宝的舌头上
I'll glue myself to SpongeBob's tongue
只要躲在那煎炸厨师的脸上
By hiding right in that fry cook's face
就可以刚刚好采样到一份蟹黄堡了
I'll be in the perfect position
to collect a Krabby Patty sample
怎么可能会出错呢
Well, what could possibly go wrong?
巧妙的伪装
Clever disguise?
有了
Check
采样容器
Sample container?
有了
Check
胶水
Glue?
有了
Check
现在启动压迫舌头行动
Time to begin operation tongue oppressor
一天一熨斗  保证没褶皱
An iron a day keeps the wrinkles away
希望来的是推销员
I hope it's a salesman
[ 附有问候或其它写就信息的一盒糖果 ]
蜜糖传书
Candy-gram
我就爱听蜜糖传即兴诗
I just love a Poetry-Slam Candy-gram
即兴诗
Poetry?
那好吧
Well, okay
玫瑰是红的  糖果是甜的
Roses are red, candy is sweet
吃糖要用嘴  千万别用脚
Eat with your mouth, not with your feet?
好个生活小忠告
Words to live by
这就对了
That's it
快吃下甜甜的小痞老板吧
Eat the delicious little plankton
只吃一小颗糖果就行了
I'll just have one little candy
我逗谁啊
Who am I kidding?
快啊  你个白痴
Come on, you dolt
快吃我
Eat me
这颗粉红色的糖果看着就挺好吃
This pink candy looks so delicious
好
Yes
所以我要把它留给你吃  小蜗
That I saved it just for you, Gary
我非要进那个傻子的嘴巴不可
I have to get inside that mouth breather's mouth
也许得把自己伪装成上门牙医
Maybe disguise myself as a door to door dentist?
好像没那种牙医
No, that's not a thing
我踩着陈年口香糖了
I stepped in some old gum
现在把自己粘到他的丑舌头上就行了
And now, I just have to glue myself to his hideous tongue
快啊
Come on
好
Yes
拗口
绕口令
小册
拗口绕口令小册
"The Tiny Book of Tortuous Tongue Twisters"
拿来晨练刚刚好
Perfect for my morning exercises
我舌头得状态良好才能吃蟹黄堡
My tongue has to be in tip top shape to taste my patties
绕口令
Tongue twisters?
怪鳕小队
"The squad of odd cod
鼓掌欢迎轻狂头足类
applaud the sassy cephalopod"
疼死了
The pain
蟹堡王
奇计顺利已在即
This dream scheme gone full steam
尤金必定惊爆鸣
guarantees Eugene's screams
天啊
Oh, boy
拗到我口了
Now, I'm doing it
早安  章鱼哥
Morning, Squidward
你口气有股海霸糊味
Your breath smells like chum
确实有点臭
It is a bit stinky
你穿越蜗牛的肠道试试
You try passing through a snail's intestines
看你有多香
and see what you smell like
喷点口气清新剂应该就行了
A little breath spray should help
来搬出冰库的肉饼  准备今天的餐点
Better get some patties out of the freezer
for today's orders
不好了
Oh, no
肉饼用光了
We're out of patties
还真是
Of course, you are
所以我可以再做新一批肉饼了
Which means I get to make a whole new batch
万岁
Hooray
还更好了
Even better
可以坐前排观赏全过程了
I'll have a front-row seat to the whole process
一点机密食材A
A little secret ingredient A
机密食材A
Secret ingredient A?
两团B
Two plops of B
一点CDE还有G
Some C, D, E, and G
两杯这个
Two cups of this
一罐那个
A jar of that
再加一小撮Z
And just a pinch of Z
这家伙在做什么鬼
What's this guy making?
字母汤吗
Alphabet soup?
拌匀
Mix well
完美
Perfect
来试试口味
Now for the taste test
这就对了  宝贝
That's it, baby
只要一份样本就行
I only need one sample
我的眼睛
My eye
这肉饼有点没味道啊
These patties are kind of bland
尝不了一点
I can't taste them at all
来发挥一点点创意吧
Time to get a little creative
加点林堡奶酪应该就有味道了
Maybe some Limburger cheese will help
不行
Oh, no
别加林堡奶酪啊
Not Limburger
还是没味
Still blah
那就来加一点德国酸菜
How about a little sauerkraut?
飞天魔鬼辣椒
Flying Dutchman peppers
还有他的陈年足垢罐头
And this old jar of toe jam
海神王啊
Good, Neptune
别吃进你嘴里啊
Not in your mouth
还是一点味道都没有
Still doesn't have any taste
原来我犯了个天大的错误
I've made a critical error
我胶水把那傻子的味蕾给盖住了
My glue has covered that dolt's taste buds
动作快点  海绵宝宝
Get a move on, SpongeBob
点餐单都快堆成山了
The orders are piling up
没问题  章鱼哥
No problem, Squidward
看来只能凑合用了
I guess it'll have to do
蟹黄堡都准备好了  章鱼哥
The Krabby Patties are ready, Squidward
随你便
Whatever
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
我都饿坏了
I'm starving
总算来了
Finally
这还是吃的吗
Is this even food?
恶心死了
This is disgusting
再也不来这吃了
I'll never eat here again
我还吃过更好吃的垃圾呢
I've had better garbage
比海霸糊还难吃
It tastes worse than chum
比海霸糊难吃吗
Worse than chum?
你把我蟹黄堡怎么了
What have you done to my patties?
抱歉  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
蟹黄堡今天一点味道都没有
The patties have no flavor at all today
没味道吗
No flavor?
味道太重了才对吧
More like too much flavor
简直跟飞天魔鬼的长内裤一个味
They taste like the Flying Dutchman's long johns
你的味蕾恐怕已经劳累过度了  小子
I'm afraid your taste buds are worn out, boy-o
你舌头没康复
Until your tongue recovers
就先别做蟹黄堡了
you're off grill duty
把帽子跟锅铲交上来
Turn in your hat and spatula
这回又失败了
That's one more for the failure pile
该弃舌逃命了
Time to abandon tongue
该死
Blast
拉链被胶水粘住了
The zipper's covered in glue
我左边胳肢窝的声音还是有点尖
My left armpit still sounds a little sharp
好听多了
That's better
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
派大星
Hey, Patrick
怎么了
What's the matter?
我尝不出味道了
I can't taste a thing
我舌头坏了
My tongue is broken
他居然会去请教派大星
He goes to Patrick for advice?
好个先傻带动后傻
It's the nitwits leading the dimwits
你舌头很可能就只是脏了
Your tongue's probably just dirty
我就老是那样子
That happens to me all the time
你简直是史上最聪明的大聪明了
You're the smartest smart person who ever smarted
奏个决胜曲吧  音乐大师
Give me a little run off music, maestro
海神王啊
Sweet Neptune
不要
No
得要强力点的东西
I need something stronger
洗船场
这个应该就行了
This should do the trick
当心热蜡
你帽子能借用一下吗  先生
May I borrow your hat, sir?
当然能了
Of course
味道分外空虚
It tastes like emptiness
我觉得味道还好吧
Tastes fine to me
我可怜的舌头劳累过度了
My poor tongue is just worn out
看来该换条新舌头了
Guess it's time for a new one
什么
What?
我可真傻
Silly me
我咋没早点这么做
Why didn't I do this earlier?
我能借你那条肮脏的旧舌头吗
Can I borrow that dirty old tongue of yours?
当然可以了
Of course
派大星吃蟹黄堡吃得比谁都多
Patrick eats more Krabby Patties than anyone
我咋没早点这么做
Why didn't I do this earlier?
抱歉  我的旧舌头有点吵
Sorry, my old tongue's a little loud
没事
That's okay
刚刚好
Perfect
我要去随便吃点东西了
I'm just gonna go grab a bite to eat
到一年一度海霸大胃王比赛大吃特吃
at the annual Chum Eating Contest
海霸大胃王比赛
大奖
Chum eating contest?
今天就办吗
Was that today?
各就各位
On your marks
预备
get set
海霸糊
chum
凭什么我就没法有个可拆卸的舌头
Why can't I have a detachable tongue?